

MMF CANDIDATE · U OF T 45 Charles St E, Toronto, ON, Canada

□ (+1) 647-936-5550 | Stianyu.ren@mail.utoronto.ca | Ashin2suka.github.io | In shin2suka | In tianyu-shin-ren

"Velut arbor ævo."

Summary_

Current MMF Candidate at U of T. 2nd Place and Best Visualization in 2019 DataFest Competition. Proficient in Python (Pytorch, Numpy, sk-learn, Pandas), R, SQL, MATLAB and Excel. Experienced in machine learning and deep learning. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools to apply in finance.

Education

Master of Mathematical Finance, University of Toronto

Toronto, CA

CANDIDATE

Aug. 2019 - Present

Relevant Course: Data Science; Pricing Theory; Stochastic Analysis; Volatility Modeling; Investment&Finance; Numerical Methods for Finance

Honours Bachelor of Science, University of Toronto, GPA: 3.87/4.0

Toronto, CA

APPLIED MATHEMATICS IN FINANCE (SPECIALIST), STATISTICS (MAJOR) AND COMPUTER SCIENCE (MINOR)

Sept. 2015 - Apr. 2019

- Relevant Course: Real Analysis; Numerical Methods; Stochastic Processes; Probability Theory; Multivariate Data Analysis, Time Series; Optimization; Machine Learning; Statistical Learning; Deep Learning; Databases
- Dean's List Scholar (Faculty of Arts and Science)
- New College Student Council In-Course Scholarship
- Student Ambassador, Department of Computer Science

Work Experience

Teaching Assistant Toronto, CA

University of Toronto Sept. 2018 – Apr. 2019

- Running tutorials, holding office hour and marking tests for a first-year Data Science course (STA130)
- Topics include: Data Visualization, Data Wrangling, Statistical Models and Machine Learning

Toronto, CA May 2018 – Aug. 2018

SCOTIABANK, GLOBAL CAPITAL MARKET TECHNOLOGY, DERIVATIVES TRADING

- Working in the Market Data System and Risk & Valuation Team, responsible for IR Curve mapping, automation PV regression testing, Inflation Swap PV testing, IR curve analytic, date utility tools(date rolling)
- Designed and Implemented an internal website for BA automation testing using Python Flask, HTML, and JavaScript, functionalities include: login/logout, automation testing and displaying results through triggering Python scripts

Awards & Projects

COMPETITION

Business Analyst

2019 2nd Place & Best Visualization, 2019 ASA DataFest at U of T

Toronto, CA

PROJECTS

Peer Mentor

2019 MNIST Handwritten Digits Recognition, University of Toronto

Toronto, CA

2019 **CNN for Image Processing**, University of Toronto

Toronto, CA

Extracurricular Activity _____

DEPARTMENT OF STATISTICAL SCIENCE, UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

Toronto, CA Jan. 2018 – *Apr.* 2018

• Assisting students in overcoming obstacles of first year in university and providing support

· Organizing group meeting sessions monthly and discussing academic and career development

May 8, 2019 Tianyu S. Ren · Résumé

Student Project Team, Event Manager

Toronto, CA

RISKLAB, UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO

Sept. 2017 - Aug. 2018

- Led a team to organize, promote and facilitate several large-scale professional events, topics including Risk Management, CFA, Big Data and FinTech
- Hosted Financial Data Case Competition by cooperating with RBC Data Analytics and proudly provided internship opportunities to the winners, where we had over 30 teams registered